SHARATH RAMESH

4405 Kendall Pointe Drive, Cumming, GA - 30028 · (312)532-9422 sharathramesh90@gmail.com · LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/sramesh9/ · GitHub: https://github.com/sharathram90

Experienced Engineer seeking the position of a Senior Test Automation Engineer to apply 6 years of test automation experience, building automation frameworks using Protractor and Mocha. Offering profound understanding of Software Development and Testing Lifecycle in an Agile Environment.

SKILLS

- Software Languages:
 - JavaScript, TypeScript, JAVA, SQL
- Database:
 - o MS SQL Server
- Project Management Tools:
 - JIRA, Axosoft
- Test Case Management Tools:
 - JIRA Test Manager, HP Quality Center, TestRail

- Source Control:
 - o GitHub, GitLabs
- Testing tools:
 - o POSTMAN, TestComplete, ReadyAPI
- Test Automation Frameworks:
 - Selenium, TestNG, Mocha, Protractor, WebDriverIO, Jasmine, Chai Assertion Library
- CI/CD:
 - Jenkins

EXPERIENCE

JAN 2019 - PRESENT

SOFTWARE ENGINEER IN TEST – TEAM LEAD, GREENSKY

- Leading a team of 4 QA Engineers by mentoring and assisting with Test Automation and Sprint testing efforts.
- Setting up UI and Test Automation frameworks using Protractor and Mocha on JavaScript/TypeScript platform for new projects, to be utilized by the team to write test scripts.
- Assisting the System Test Engineering Team by providing POCs to enable current test Automation frameworks to work with multi region services on **AWS Cloud**.
- Provided multiple solutions for the Test Engineering team to automate heavy duty and redundant manual tasks. (Refer individual projects section)
- Worked with CI/CD pipeline scripts using groovy to run automated tests as part of the deployment pipeline
- Performed Database validations and fed data for test automation frameworks using SQL on Microsoft SQL Server Studio
- Successfully delivered a POC to justify the implementation of **ReadyAPI** (developed by SmartBear) to enable mock services as part of the testing efforts.

MAY 2016 - JAN 2019

QA AUTOMATION ENGINEER, ACCESSO

- Create, maintain, and execute test cases to find defects on Angular, Flex and mobile
 applications in an Agile work environment and maintained using TestRail
- Consistently recognized and Subject Matter Expert by assisting and troubleshooting issues for Operations and Client Solutions Specialists.
- Responsible for maintaining and administering App and Web Server boxes on Linux environment using Shell Scripts
- Formulated SQL queries for back-end validation and Database Test Management using MySQL
- Implemented **Selenium** on **TestNG framework** along with **Page Object Model** to create and maintain test scripts on **JAVA** platform
- Validating REST API functionalities using POSTMAN collections
- Utilized TestComplete (by SmartBear) to automate the testing of a Point of Sale application built on Flex (Adobe AIR) platform

SEP 2015 - MAY 2016

QUALITY ASSURANCE ENGINEER II, SUMTOTAL SYSTEMS LLC (SKILLSOFT)

- Performed functional testing, System Integration Testing, Smoke testing on a HRMS/LMS web application built on AngularJS and JAVA
- Identified and prioritized test cases and maintained Test Cases using HP Quality Center
 ALM
- Reviewed requirements, specifications, user documentation with the Test Lead to identify potential risks and critical test paths as part of the test plan
- Created SQL scripts to automate data validation of records imported through files with delimiters
- Maintained and executed automated test scripts for the UI application using Selenium
 Webdriver on a jUnit framework

SEP 2012 - JULY 2013

ASSISTANT SYSTEMS ENGINEER, TATA CONSULTANCY SERVICES

- Gained knowledge and successfully implemented the concepts of Software Testing
 Lifecycle and Defect Lifecycle for an e-commerce Web Application
- Implemented Selenium IDE for record and playback of manually executed test cases
- Collaborated with team members and team leads to develop test strategies for new user stories.

EDUCATION

MAY 2015

MASTER OF SCIENCE (M.S.), ILLINOIS INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, CHICAGO

GPA: 3.24/4.00

MAJOR: Electrical and Computer Engineering

MAY 2012

BACHELOR OF ENGINEERING (B.E.), ANNA UNIVERSITY, INDIA

GPA: 3.15/4.00

MAJOR: Electrical and Electronics Engineering

INDIVIDUAL PROJECTS

• Artifacts File Migration tool

This tool was developed to aid the Test Engineering Team to make use of the artifacts files that resided in the web server boxes for each environment. They were also accessible only through Jenkins. These files had huge chunks of XML data that needed to be validated as part of our testing efforts. The script that I developed implemented SSH access methods to login to the web server boxes and copied over the artifacts files to the local repository of the user using the Nodejs file handling library (fs). Once copied over the file will be read by the script and will return the data in JSON format for automated data validations

• JIRA Subtask Automation

This script was developed to automate the creation of subtasks in JIRA. As part of the Test Engineering we are supposed to create subtasks under user stories to track our work and estimate sprint velocity. This was a repetitive and time consuming task since we had to create 4-5 subtasks for all user stories for every sprint. In order to speed up this process I made use of JIRA public API documentation which had information about the endpoints to use for creating subtasks. The script would take the following arguments as input in the form of an Array object and create subtasks accordingly.

- User story id
- Sub task title
- Assignee